Cool, so we've set it
up so that when our
player runs into an obstacle,
it'll start the death animation.
But there is one small
problem that we actually
need to fix, which
is when we press the
spacebar, we're actually
still able to jump and that's
definitely not something
that should be possible.
So we're going to need
to change our code just
a little bit so that way
we don't just magically
jump even though technically the
game is over and the player has died.
Now in order to prevent
our player from jumping
over and over again
when the game is over
and they've lost, we'll actually need to
change the condition of our if statement.
So perfectly fine that
they press spacebar and
they can jump and to make sure that
they are on the ground when they jump.
But we do need to make
sure that the game is not over
otherwise they'll still be able
to jump when the game is over.
So we're going to add
an and symbol here, so
two ampersands for
and and then we're going
to use if game over equals equals false.
So if the game is not
over then this thing will run.
In fact there's actually an
easier way that we can do this.
So we can actually use what's called
an exclamation point and set this to true.
So in this case the exclamation point
actually negates the statement after it.
So if game over is not equal to true.
So the same thing as saying game over equals
equals false, then it will do this thing.
In fact there's actually even a shorter way
that we can write if the game is not over
for Boolean values
we can actually just put
that exclamation point
in front of game over.
So in this case this
says if the game is not
over because of this
exclamation point then
do these lines of code.
Now if I save we can see if this code
really worked when we press play.
So if we press space
we can still jump and
then if we hit one of
the barriers the player
runs into it and then we press the
space bar and we can't jump anymore.
So a really easy way
that we can prevent the
player from jumping
after the game is over.
So what you're going to do is in your update
method in the player controller you're
going to add in your if
statement another and
comparison so you can
chain them all together.
So if the space bar is down and the player
is on the ground and the game is not over
so all of these have to be
true then this will happen.
Now it's your turn.